Joshua Siverson

Email: siversonj@gmail.com | 1(208) 318-6206 | San Francisco, CA
Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

Three strong years in Business Development. Proven experience as a Web Developer where I created more than ten front and back-end web apps. Keen understanding and knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js with experience in MERN Stack. Proactively expanding my front-end development skills to maximize users interaction and experience.

Technical Skills

Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Handlebars, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React Native, GIT, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, writing tests

Education

University of California, Berkeley Ext.

September 2017 - Dec. 2017

Javascript Full Stack Web Development

Immersive 12-week program dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned includes HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js.

Northwest Nazarene University

August 2008 - May 2012

Dual Major: Business Administration & Economics | GPA: 3.75

Applications Built

- → <u>Friday Fun Finder</u> Web app created to source events happening near a user's area that pulls in several API's
 - ◆ Tech used HTML, API's, AJAX, CSS, JS, jQuery, Animate.css library, Firebase Database
- → Media-CLI- Bot- Command line Bot allowing user to search for movies, songs and Tweets.
 - ◆ Tech used Node.js, NPM, API's (Twitter, Spotify, IMDB), AJAX
- → Train-Scheduler Web app for users to create train schedules and display with proper intervals.
 - ◆ Tech used IS, CSS, Moment.js, Firebase,

Previous Experience

App Annie- Enterprise Business Development

February 2016-March 2017

- → FY '16- 110% KPI performance attainment
- → Ranked #1 in Business Development among 400+ person company

Evernote- Account Executive **R.R. Donnelley-** Account Executive

October 2014-February 2016 July 2012-October 2014